TEN (ENVELOPE)
[narrator] Ten:
The ability to envelop your body
in a shroud of Nen aura,
making it tougher
and slowing the effects of aging.
ZETSU (SUPPRESS)
Zetsu:
A technique which shuts off
your flow of Nen aura.
Effective for concealing your presence
and recovering from fatigue.
REN (REFINE)
Ren:
A technique for creating
an especially strong Nen aura.
It is crucial for increasing your power.
HATSU (RELEASE)
Hatsu:
The release of your Nen aura,
after using Ren to boost it.
These four elements
are known as the Four Exercises
and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
FOUR EXERCISES
[theme song playing]
Gon.
You and me, we’ve got to learn
all that we can about Nen.
Yeah!
AN x EMPTY x THREAT
[narrator] After two months during which
Gon was forbidden to practice Nen,
Wing summoned Gon and Killua
to his room for a meeting.
[Wing] Gon, Killua.
Starting today, you will be
training alongside Zushi.
And Gon, splendid work.
I’m happy to see
that you kept your promise.
It’s because of your promise thread.
There were a couple of times
I got really close to giving in.
But then I’d look at the thread,
and I could feel myself getting calmer.
Because I imbued it with Nen to help you.
Wait… Really?
No. I was kidding.
[Gon] Uh...
Hold on.
How can you tell
Gon’s been keeping his promise?
As far as you know,
he was secretly cheating this whole time.
Because the promise thread
is completely intact.
Gon. I know it’s been a while,
but would you show me your Ten?
-You sure?
-Yes.
Oh, man…
Do I even remember how?
It's been so long.
I wonder if I can still pull it off.
[Wing] What do you think, Zushi?
It-- It’s amazing!
His aura is flowing completely
around him, sir!
It’s soft and tranquil…
but it’s-- it’s so powerful, too!
That’s it!
What a relief!
I was worried that
I had forgotten how to do it.
Once you’ve learned the technique,
it can’t be forgotten.
However, in order to become a true master,
you will have to practice diligently.
But it felt a lot easier
than it did before
and I haven’t practiced Ten
in a real long time.
I can explain.
That’s because you’ve been
training your spirit every day.
Now please look at your left hand.
What?
It broke!
I tied the thread to your finger
with my own Nen,
so if you had broken your promise,
the thread would’ve broken as well.
[Killua] You can do stuff like that?
Question, Mister Wing:
You saw Hisoka and Kastro’s match?
[Wing] Yes, I did.
So, what was Hisoka’s ability?
Do you think we could do that?
Send our limbs flying all over the place?
[Wing] Hmm...That's a difficult question.
Gon. Have you seen
a recording of the fight?
No. Not yet, sir.
Then I’ll explain while we watch.
[audience cheering]
[Wing] There.
See the strands of aura extending out
from his left hand?
[Gon] “Strands of aura”?
Yes.
Do you see them?
[Killua grunts, focusing]
No… I don’t think so…
I can’t see anything…
Me neither, sir.
[focusing grunt, focusing grumble]
[Gon] Are there really strands of aura
coming out of his left hand?
Are you sure?
I am.
See, Hisoka is using a technique
that makes his aura exceedingly difficult
to perceive.
SUPPRESS
It’s a high-level application of Zetsu,
known as “In”.
CONCEAL
It renders even powerful aura
invisible to your opponent.
And to counter this,
you must focus all of your Ren
in both of your eyes,
utilizing a technique known as Gyo.
GYO (FOCUS)
The method Gon used
in his fight with Gido
might also be useful.
But you can’t counterattack,
so you’d ultimately get yourself killed.
Right…
[Wing] My assignment for the two of you
is to practice Ren,
until you can see through Hisoka’s In.
But Master…
What about me?
What kind of training should I do?
Zushi.
You should already be just strong enough
to see past Hisoka’s In.
You think so?
[Wing] If you would,
please show them your Ren.
[determined grunt]
O-- Osu!
[focusing exhale]
[shouts] Ren!
It's so strong.
It’s just as big as ours…
but the aura is so much more dense!
Now focus that aura into your eyes.
[Zushi] Osu!
[focusing effort]
And Gyo!
Good.
So, tell me, can you see the aura
rushing from his body?
[straining]
Yes.
There are individual strands of aura.
How many of them do you see?
Twelve… Wait.
No. I think I count 13, sir.
Not quite.
But you are very close indeed.
[tired exhale, panting]
I really could see them!
You’re really making
excellent progress, Zushi.
Osu! Thank you! I’m trying, Master.
By channeling every ounce
of your power through Gyo,
you achieved a level where you could see
through Hisoka’s In.
But with enough training,
you’ll be able to use Gyo
even while you’re fighting.
Now do you understand?
First, practice using Ren
and master the application known as Gyo.
Then and only then
will you discover
the true nature of Hisoka’s ability.
You asked if you would ever be able
to use that same ability.
And my answer is yes,
but at the same time, no.
[both] Huh?
Regardless of what his power is,
so long as it uses Nen,
you’ll be able to learn it.
But it’s important to note
that Nen abilities
depend on the individual.
Because of course, we each possess
different specialties and preferences
which means that Nen differs
for each person.
If you’re serious about mastering Nen,
you shouldn’t merely copy
the abilities of others.
You need to first identify
your own particular strengths.
Strengths, huh?
[Wing] You’re still growing,
so you haven’t settled on one form yet.
My advice is to enrich yourself
as much as possible.
That is the purpose of your training.
Train with all of your might.
Play just as hard.
And enjoy life!
[Zushi, Gon and Killua] Osu!
I believe the last day of Killua’s window
to compete is June ninth.
And Gon, yours is the tenth, correct?
Both of you should register to fight
on your final day.
In the meantime, you'll train.
You must both learn Gyo
before you enter battle.
[Gon, Killua and Zushi] Osu!
[Gon] Hey, Zushi!
Your Ren was impressive!
You got way ahead of us
while I was stuck recuperating.
No. I’ve still got a long way to go.
Hey! Why don’t we practice a little.
It should be fun!
Okay. Then let’s go up to your room, Gon.
Mm hm.
Zushi. Killua.
I feel it.
We’ve got company, guys.
[elevator dings]
You don’t give up, do you?
That isn’t the way to make friends.
Now, that’ll be enough of that.
Just tell us when you’re going to fight,
because I’m dying to be your opponent.
[light chuckle]
[Killua snorts]
I guess these guys
specialize in hunting newbies.
This is what they do.
Get wins beating us up.
[Sadaso] We’re getting desperate here.
See, our deadline is approaching.
C’mon. We wanna fight. [light chuckle]
I’ll even demonstrate my power for you,
right here and now.
How about that?
Okay. I’m gonna be fighting
on June the tenth.
Hey! Gon!
That won’t work for me.
I’m sorry to tell you,
but my deadline is May 29th.
Fight on that day.
Who cares about your stupid deadline,
you idiot?
Let’s get going.
Gon, my friend…
You and I will fight.
I guarantee it. [light chuckle]
It’s a promise.
[Killua] Come on. Ignore him.
What are you gonna do?
I’m going to force him to fight me.
[snickers]
[Killua]
Visualize energy building up in your body.
Feel the power from each
and every cell… gathering.
Growing and growing…
Then, all of a sudden,
force that power out!
[tired exhale]
I’m getting the hang of it!
The timing to get Ten
to contain that aura
was a little bit tricky.
[Zushi] Wait… a little?!
How are they picking it up so fast?
But Zushi’s aura is stronger.
We’re not even close to matching him yet.
Guess we ought to train more.
[Zushi] Uh… N-no! That’s enough.
Learning when to rest
is a big part of training.
Why don’t we just call it a day.
Really? Cause I ca--
I told you no!
If they surpass me in half a day,
I’ll lose all my motivation!
What’s the deal?
Oh, it’s fine.
So more tomorrow?
Works for me.
I’ll see you again tomorrow.
Take it easy!
All right, then.
[elevator dings]
[light chuckle]
[smirks]
[gasps]
[straining]
[Zushi] I can’t--
I can’t…. move!
I can’t talk or breathe, either!
What’s going on?!
Oops.
It’s your turn.
All right.
[Gido's prosthetic leg
tapping on the pavement]
[snickers]
[Killua] Knock it off.
I figured you might be up to something.
But forget the dirty tricks.
You want a fight, fine.
Which day do you want?
Oh, and don’t worry.
I’ll let you win, ok?
Wait. How about I give all of you a win?
Good enough?
Once I get my win against you,
your friend Gon will be my next victim.
If you wanna fight Gon,
you’ll have to work around his schedule.
Something tells me
you’ll be happy to.
In fact, I can guarantee it.
[Sadaso chuckling]
[Sadaso] Okay.
If the two of you are willing to fight,
it’ll save us the trouble
of using tactics like this one.
What do you say we all register together?
Once that’s done,
we’ll return the boy unharmed.
Yeah, sure. Okay.
But this is absolutely the very last time.
You got that?
There. May 29th.
Done. You happy now?
Yes.
We’ll return your friend here.
And up we go.
Oh. I’ll say it again -
It’s the last time.
And if you break your promise…
[Killua sighs]
Whatever.
Forget it.
[Riehlvelt] What? I’m curious…
What’s going to happen
if we break our promise?
[Killua]
There’s no point in telling you now.
Just keep your end of the deal, okay?
[smirks]
[ringing]
Hello? Is this Gon?
I don’t think I have to tell you
what this means.
As long as you don’t tell anyone
and you follow my instructions
to the letter,
the three of you will be able
to train tomorrow,
just like you planned.
[Gon] Zushi…
So how did it go with Gon?
[Gido] Perfectly.
He’s registered for the thirtieth.
[snickers] That makes two victories.
Too easy.
[Sadaso cackling]
Not killing people
is harder than I thought it’d be.
Ah, man.
Honest living is tough.
[scalper] Step right up!
Get your tickets here!
These are hot off the presses,
ladies and gents!
Gon versus Sadaso!
We’ve got Killua versus Sadaso, too!
Better buy ‘em now
or you’re gonna regret it!
-[Killua] Hey pops.
-‘Sup, kid?
That Sadaso guy has just one arm?
[scalper] That’s right!
The one-armed fighter
with a face like a mask.
If he grabs you
with his invisible left arm,
you’re done.
See… they call him
the newbie hunter and--
That son of a…
[Gon] Killua? Hey…
Gon. This is where you’ve been?
Uh… yeah…
Killua.
I hear that you helped Zushi
home last night.
Thank you.
Are you feeling all right?
Yeah. I’m fine.
I was probably just tired, that’s all.
I’m sorry to worry you!
Oh. Hey, Mister Wing.
Do you think that we can
watch that video again?
Cause I figured out how to use Gyo.
Huh?! Really?
Fifteen threads, right?
Thirteen for the cards,
one more for the scarf
and one well-hidden one
for the arm he tossed.
And then…
Keep going.
Hisoka’s aura.
It almost looks like...
it’s expanding and contracting.
Or does it attract certain objects
like a magnet does?
How else would his arm reattach itself?
Not to mention flying off
and targeting Kastro’s jaw?
My money is on the former.
I think his aura must be stretchy,
like rubber or something.
And if it is,
then that would explain
most of his magic tricks.
He’s on a completely different level!
You pass. That’s very good.
Although, I am a little surprised.
I certainly never expected both of you
to actually learn Gyo overnight.
Both of us?
Yep. But I still couldn’t figure out
what Hisoka’s ability was.
-[Zushi sighs]
-So, Killua,
I’m sure now
that you’ve finished your assignment,
you’ll be wanting to fight soon, correct?
It’s okay.
I didn’t mean to beat you to the punch.
I guess I just got
an itch to fight, that’s all.
Yeah. I understand.
They must ‘a threatened you.
Huh, Gon?
Actually, I’ve already chosen
my day to fight.
I signed up for May 29th.
I’m fighting on May 30th.
All right, fine.
I guess I underestimated your progress.
It’s quite impressive.
Between now and your scheduled fights
practice both Ten and Ren.
And in addition to your training,
get plenty of rest and sleep.
[Gon and Killua] Osu!
-[Gon] Killua.
-[Killua] Hm?
[Gon] Those guys threatened you, too,
didn’t they?
That makes me so mad…
Yeah. But still…
my biggest concern
was getting Wing’s permission.
[Gon] I guess my biggest concern is
that they’ll do
the same thing to Zushi again.
[Killua] It’s okay.
You don't need to worry.
[Sadaso]
Today, I'll beat Killua for my sixth win.
Tomorrow, I'll beat Gon
for my seventh win.
After that,
all I’ll need to do
is find three more suckers...
[chuckling]
...then I’ll be a Floor Master!
With the kind of fame and fortune
that’ll get me,
I’ll be set for the rest of my life!
[gasps]
[Killua] You move, you die.
You use Nen and you die.
Make a sound and you die.
If you understand, close your eyes.
Do you see what happens
when you break your promises?
If you do, open your eyes,
look at me in the mirror
and listen carefully.
Don’t ever show your dirty face
in front of us again.
You’ll keep this promise.
[referee] Sadaso’s time is up!
Killua wins by default!
[spectator] Are you kidding me?
What is this?
[disgruntled spectators shouting]
[narrator] Killua opens the battle
against the persistent trio
with a technical victory.
Thanks to their unique natural talents,
the real battle at Heavens Arena
is only just beginning for Gon and Killua
who are learning Nen at incredible speed!
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we’ll be introducing Sadaso!
He went through the traditional initiation
with Gido and Riehlvelt. [giggles]
One arm’s invisible
cause it’s made of Nen. [giggles]
That’s right!
[Gon] Next time: “Power To Avenge”!
Power… right?
[Killua] Avenge... right?
[Gon and Killua] Right? Right? Right?